Hello it's Scott Manley here.
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/HGICHa1IZKo
原视频发布日期：20200603
原作者名：Scott Manley
大家好 这里是Scott Manley
Last week we saw Bob and Doug fly to the space station on the Dragon 2.
上周我们看到Bob和Doug乘坐龙2飞船前往空间站
A long-awaited return to flight for US human launch capabilities.
这次发射期待已久 让美国重获载人发射能力
这里的私人其实指不上市公司(私营公司)，与波音，洛马这种上市公司(公众公司)对比
也是人类首次使用私人建造的火箭入轨的飞行
And the first flight of humans to orbit on a privately built booster.
但这只是漫长旅程的结束
But this was merely the end of a long journey
牵涉到很多人 这些人将塑造美国的太空政策
that involved many people who would shape US space policy.
所以我想问 我们是怎么走到今天的？
So I want to ask how did we get here?
And to understand this you have to go back to
要理解这个问题 你必须回到
the tragic loss of the Space Shuttle Columbia and her crew in 2003.
2003年哥伦比亚号航天飞机不幸失事 其机组人员不幸遇难
At that time a committee of experts were appointed to investigate.
当时任命了一个专家委员会进行调查
They were named the Columbia Accident Investigation Board.
这被命名为哥伦比亚号事故调查委员会
And for some of them, the more they found out about the Space Shuttle, the less safe it seemed to be.
委员会中的一些人认为 他们对航天飞机了解的越多 就觉得航天飞机越不安全
Some of them on the accident investigation board actually wanted it grounded permanently.
事故调查委员会中的一些人实际上希望将它永久停飞
One problem they highlighted was that the retirement date had been set by NASA based upon
他们强调的一个问题是 NASA设定的航天飞机退役日期是基于
when they expected a successor to be available.
当他们预计航天飞机会有继任者的时候
In 2001 when the X-33 was canceled, the date of retirement was pushed back from 2012 to 2020.
2001年X-33被取消时 退役日期从2012年推迟到2020年
The final board reports suggest that the Space Shuttles could be kept flying up until 2010
最后的委员会报告表明 航天飞机可以一直飞到2010年
with the prospect of inspection and refurbishment to extend their life.
有望通过检查和整修以续命
The Shuttles were old in years
按年份来讲 航天飞机已经很旧了
but they were young in terms of the flight time they'd been developed for.
但就它们的飞行时间而言 它们还图样很年轻 而飞行时间才是它们的开发标准
They had expected weekly or monthly flights back when they were originally designed.
最初设计航天飞机的时候 预计它们每周或每月都会进行飞行
but they couldn't build replacements at least not affordably.
但他们无法制造足够廉价的替换零件
The last time a Shuttle had been built was Endeavour
上一个建造的航天飞机是奋进号
and that was cobbled together over two spare parts.
而这是由两批备用零件拼凑而成的
So restarting production would have been about as expensive as developing an entirely new launch vehicle.
因此 重新开始生产的费用 将与开发一个全新的运载火箭差不多
In 2004, the president announced the way forward with the his Vision for Space Exploration.
在2004年 总统宣布了未来的太空计划 他的太空探索愿景
Shuttle was to be set for retirement in 2010
航天飞机将于2010年退役
likely based upon the conclusions that the Accident Investigation Board had delivered.
很可能是基于事故调查委员会所做的结论
In the same speech he also talks about a new generation of crew exploration vehicle.
在同一篇演讲中 他还谈到了新一代载人探索航天器
No new development money was immediately available.
目前还不能马上筹措到新的开发资金
However there were a number of projects already in development in NASA, which might fit the bill.
然而NASA已经有一些开发中的项目可能符合这个要求
A year later NASA began something called the Commercial Orbital Transportation Services Program.
一年后 NASA开始了一个叫做商业轨道运输服务项目的东西
it had long been a dream of many to make commercial space services a reality.
长期以来 许多人的梦想着使商业太空服务成为现实
NASA wanted to generate demand
NASA希望通过这样的方式产生商业轨道运输需求
by asking private companies to deliver cargo to the International Space Station.
也就是要求私人公司向国际空间站运送货物
And there was a lot of resistance from people to the idea
而且人们对这个想法有很大的抵触情绪
but the cargo delivery was seen as lower risk than other options.
但货物运输被认为比其他的选项风险更低
Because the world alternatives for cargo delivery from Japan, Europe and Russia
因为世界上譬如日本 欧洲和俄罗斯都可以运输货物
and that could fill in if things went wrong or were delayed.
并在出现问题或延误的情况下可以进行补充
So the program was to be managed by the Commercial Crew & Cargo Program Office.
所以这个项目要由商业载人和货物项目办公室来管理
Also known as C3PO.
也就是C3PO
And with approval of their President and Congress,
并得到总统和国会的批准
500 million dollars was set aside to fund initial development of technologies required for commercial services.
拨出5亿美元用于资助商业服务所需技术的初步开发
So instead of strict requirements, there were guidelines on what was needed
因此 不是制定了关于严格要求 而是需求的指导方针
such as the ability to launch 8.4 tons of cargo to the International Space Station every year.
如每年能向国际空间站发射8.4吨货物
with no specification on the number of flights required or any stipulations on how the vehicle should be designed
而没有规定所需的飞行次数 也没有规定航天器的设计方式
Unlike the Space Shuttle, NASA wouldn't own the launch vehicles or the spacecraft,
与航天飞机不同 NASA不会拥有火箭或者航天器
it would simply be buying rides on them.
而只会按照飞行次数来购买
The intellectual property would remain with the developer.
知识产权仍将归开发商所有
Also the program stipulated that the development money awarded had to be matched by private investors
此外 该计划还规定 获得的开发资金必须由私人投资者来提供
to prevent companies being purely reliant on NASA money.
以防止公司仅仅依赖NASA的资金
The first request for proposals began in January 2006
第一次招标于2006年1月开始
and twenty-one proposals were delivered before the March sixth deadline
并在3月6日截止日期前 得到了21份提案
and these came from a range of companies including existing NASA suppliers like Lockheed, Boeing,
而这些提案来自一系列公司 包括NASA现有的供应商 洛克希德 波音等等
through the new space startups that we knew today such as SpaceX
以及我们今天所熟知的新兴太空创业公司 比如SpaceX公司
and at least according to one account, somebody who was going to build a rocket engine in their garage.
而且至少听说过 有人要在车库里造一个火箭发动机
After the selection process, the two finalists chosen were
经过层层选拔 最终入选的两个项目分别是
SpaceX who had pitched a larger version of their Falcon 1 rocket, the Falcon 9
SpaceX公司提出过他们的猎鹰1号火箭的更大版本 即猎鹰9号
and Rocketplane Kistler with their K1 reused rocket running on high-performance Russian engines.
和Rocketplane Kistler公司的K1可重复使用火箭 其使用高性能的俄罗斯发动机
At this point SpaceX had tried one launch of its Falcon 1 rocket which had failed.
此时SpaceX已经尝试过发射一次猎鹰1号火箭 但失败了
And in 2006 was the year then that the Constellation Program got her name.
而在2006年 星座计划被命名
Bits of it had been in development since 2001
从2001年开始 它的部分内容就已经开始研发了
but this brought them all together under one roof.
但项目命名后 所有的工作就聚集在了一起
It was an ambitious program using Shuttle-derived hardware for the Ares 1 and Ares 5 rockets
这是一个雄心勃勃的计划 把航天飞机衍生的部件用在战神1和战神5火箭上
which would launch a new crew exploration vehicle, which we now know as Orion.
它将发射一个新的载人探索航天器 也就是我们现在所知的猎户座飞船
The Crew Exploration Vehicle had been conceived in the 1990s with official planning beginning in 2004
载人探索航天器是在20世纪90年代构想的 在2004年开始正式规划
and the contract being awarded to Lockheed in 2006.
并在2006年将合同授予洛克希德公司
And as you know, it's still not really ready.
如你所知 它现在仍然没有真正准备好
Anyway, the Constellation Program was pitched as being the replacement for the Space Shuttle
总之 星座计划是作为航天飞机的替代品而提出的
and the program that would take astronauts back to the moon.
同时它也能把航天员带回月球
The Ares 1 would use a single solid say a five segment rocket booster
战神1号将使用一个五段式固体火箭助推器（作为1级）
derived from the Shuttle design which only has four segments.
源于航天飞机（固体助推器）的设计 尽管那个只有4个分段
It would have an upper stage that was powered by a J-2X engine develop a burning hydrogen and oxygen.
它的上面级由J-2X氢氧发动机驱动
The Ares 5 on the other hand was a monster heavy lift vehicle a bit like the SLS
战神5则是有点像SLS的重型运载火箭
but bigger and able to put 188 tons into low-earth orbit.
但更大 能把188吨的东西送入低地轨道
In 2007 the agreement with Kistler was then terminated
2007年 与Kistler的协议被终止
because they had been unable to raise the private funds needed to match the NASA money.
因为他们一直无法筹集到与NASA资金相匹配的私人资金
And another rental proposals were were made.
而NASA采纳了另一个租赁提案
NASA chose instead Orbital Sciences Corporation with their Cygnus cargo vehicle
也就是轨道科学公司和他们的天鹅座货运飞船
and the Taurus 2 rocket which is now known as the Antares.
以及现在被称为心宿二的金牛座2号火箭
Meanwhile SpaceX was in trouble.
与此同时 SpaceX公司也遇到了麻烦
The Falcon 1 rocket launchers were failing to reach orbit.
猎鹰1号火箭未能入轨
The first three flights were all failures
前三次飞行都失败了
and Elon Musk often mentions how SpaceX would have shut down if the fourth flight had not succeeded.
也就是马一龙经常提到的事情 如果第四次发射也没有成功 SpaceX就会倒闭
And you'll be unsurprised to hear that in 2008 they succeeded their first launch of a Falcon 1 rocket
而不让人吃惊地是 在2008年 他们完成了猎鹰1号火箭的首次成功发射
paving the way for their one only commercial launch of the Falcon 1 in 2009.
为2009年猎鹰1号的唯一一次商业发射奠定了基础
2009 would also see a new president and one of the first space policy decisions he made
2009年 新总统上任 他做出的第一个太空政策决定就是
was to create a committee to study the current state of affairs.
要成立一个委员会来研究目前的状况
Officially known as the review of United States human space flight plans committee.
正式名称为美国载人航天飞行计划审查委员会
Better known as the Augustine Commission after the chairman Norman Augustine.
以主席诺曼奥古斯丁的名字 更被称为奥古斯丁委员会
He actually chaired a similar Commission 20 years earlier
其实20年前他就主持过类似的委员会
and so he had a lot of respect at doing this kind of thing.
所以他在做这种事情的时候很受尊重
So the Commission did their work
所以委员会完成了他们的工作
在他们的报告中 我想强调的两件事是
and there was two important things that I want to highlight in their report.
第一 他们发现商业服务的发展超出了预期
The first was that they found the commercial services development were exceeding expectations
他们立即建议增加这方面的资金
and they immediately recommended more funding for this.
我想他们几乎马上就得到了额外的两亿美元
I think they got two hundred million dollars extra almost right away.
但是他们也发现星座计划的资金从来没有达到完成目标所需的水平
But they also find the Constellation Program had never been funded at the levels required to hit its targets.
And at the current funding levels,
而在目前的资金水平上
they estimated it would be as late as 2020
他们估计要到2020年
before it was able to launch a single crew to the International Space Station.
才能够向国际空间站发射一个乘员
And so in response to this space policy changed.
于是回应这种情况 太空政策发生了变化
The president drove a stronger commitment to commercial space services.
总统加强了对商业航天服务的资金投入
Not only approving the Commercial Resupply Services Program
不仅批准了商业再补给服务计划(CRS)
that paid SpaceX and Orbital Sciences for delivering cargo to the ISS,
该计划给SpaceX和轨道科学支付了向国际空间站运送货物的费用
but in 2010, the Commercial Crew Development Program started.
但在2010年 商业载人开发计划(CCDev)开始
It was expected that
预计
Commercial Crew providers would be able to develop the capability and deliver to the ISS as early as 2015.
商业载人计划的供应商将能够最早在2015年具备载人能力 并向国际空间站运输乘员
Constellation was essentially defunded and many politicians in Congress were unhappy that with this.
星座计划基本上被取消了 许多国会的政客对此不满
Partly because they didn't really have control over the allocation of contracts to the commercial programs.
部分原因是他们无法控制商业项目的合同分配
So this really represented a loss of control and a loss of money to their states.
所以这对他们的州来说代表了一种控制权和金钱的损失
In the end the parts of Constellation that had been developed
最后 星座计划的部分零件已经被开发出来
including the Orion spacecraft and the five segment boosters and the RL-10 engines upgrades.
包括猎户座航天器和五段助推器以及RL-10发动机的升级
Those all became part of the SLS program.
这些都成为SLS计划的一部分
Meanwhile huge parts of Constellation weren't useful. Much of it was still on the drawing board
同时 星座计划的大量部件并没有用武之地 大部分还在图纸上
and the singular launch that they made was the Ares 1x
而他们所做的唯一的发射是战神1X
which took a regular four segment Shuttle booster.
它采用了一个普通的四段式航天飞机助推器
It added an extension to make it look like a five segment booster.
它增加了一个扩展段 使它看起来像一个五段助推器
They added a boilerplate upper stage
他们增加了一个模型上面级
and even that single launch with half the equipment
甚至是这样一半设备的发射
was almost as expensive as the entire Commercial Crew Development Program.
几乎和整个CCDev一样昂贵
To that point it was about four hundred million dollars.
至此 大约是花费了四亿美元
SLS was less capable than the Ares 5
SLS的性能比战神5号还差
but it was much more likely to deliver on a reasonable timescale.
但它更有可能在合理的时间范围内发射
Also the Ares 1 was considered to be much more dangerous than any other human launch options proposed.
另外 战神1号被认为比任何其他已存在的载人发射方案都要危险得多
There was a great paper on how dangerous this would have been.
有一篇不错的论文 里面说明了这将是多么地危险
In 2010 also saw the first flight of SpaceX's Falcon 9.
2010年也见证了SpaceX的猎鹰9号首飞
In fact it's 10 years ago tomorrow on Thursday
事实上 10年前的明天 也就是星期四
that the first Falcon 9 launched carrying a boilerplate upper stage simulation of the Dragon capsule.
第一枚猎鹰9号进行了发射 携带的是模拟龙飞船的上面级模型
The 1.0 version of Falcon 9 is quite different from what we know today.
1.0版本的猎鹰9号与我们今天所知道的有很大的不同
The nine engines are arranged in a grid instead of an Octaweb.
九台发动机以网格的形式排列 而不是排成8个一圈的形式
The stages are shorter
一级和二级都更短
and of course there's no landing legs or grid fins.
当然 也没有着陆腿或栅格舵
SpaceX did however include parachutes to test recovery they didn't get any success with that.
不过SpaceX确实加入了降落伞来测试回收 但是他们并没有获得任何成功
And in all of this, the most important decision was the commitment to Commercial Crew.
而在这一切中 最重要的决定是对商业载人计划投入的资金
Commercial Cargo hadn't even been demonstrated.
商业货运计划甚至还没有进行验证
So to committing to privately funded crew launches requires a lot of faith in private industry
所以要对私人资助的载人发射进行资金投入 需要对私人行业有很大的信心
being able to deliver something completely new
要相信它能提供完全新颖的东西
in a timeline faster than the existing government development process.
在时间上比现有的政府(项目)研发进程更快
So 2011 will that saw the last flight of the Space Shuttle.
那么 在2011年 航天飞机进行了最后一次发射
It actually been extended by one year to allow completion of the International Space Station.
它实际上已经被续命了一年来完成国际空间站的建造
2011 also saw SpaceX is first award from NASA to develop a crew capable version of their dragon cargo capsule.
2011年 SpaceX也得到了NASA要求研发载人版龙飞船合同的第一笔资金
In May of 2012 SpaceX became the first private company
2012年5月 SpaceX公司成为第一家私营企业
to successfully dock spacecraft to the International Space Station in Dragon Demo Flight 2.
在龙飞船第二次验证飞行中成功地将航天器与国际空间站进行对接
And later that year they began their semi regular Commercial Resupply Services missions to the station.
同年晚些时候 他们开始了对空间站的半定期商业补给服务任务
2013 brought us the Falcon 9 1.1 with the extended tanks and the silhouette that we today.
2013年 猎鹰9号1.1版为我们带来了加长的储罐和今天的轮廓
And also the first attempts at using rocket engines to land the boosters.
也首次尝试使用火箭发动机来降落一级火箭
In the early years of the Commercial Crew Program,
在商业载人计划(CCP)的早期
there were also ongoing efforts to overturn those presidential funding requests.
(国会)也一直在努力推翻这些总统的资金申请
Every few months there'll be hearings
每隔几个月就会有一次听证会
with the NASA Administrator going to Congress to ask for the program to be properly funded.
而NASA局长到国会要求为该计划提供适当的资金
This would of course be delayed development.
这当然会延缓计划的发展
The proposals they had expected you know launches as early as 2015
(CCP的)方案最早将于2015年就会开始发射
but the continual underfunding made those untenable.
但资金的持续不足使得这些都无法维持
And of course such rosy timelines didn't factor into the extra development time needed
当然 这样美好的时间表并没有考虑到额外需要的开发时间
to deal with the problems with the parachutes for example.
譬如处理降落伞的问题
2014 also saw the actual contracts being awarded for Commercial Crew Services with two finalists.
2014年还迎来了商业载人服务的实际合同授予 有两家入围
Boeing could expect to receive up to 4.2 billion while SpaceX's contract could earn it 2.6 billion.
波音公司可望获得高达42亿的合同 而SpaceX的合同为26亿
Now this isn't money that was paid out.
那么 这并不是(用于)支付(服务)的钱
This is the flights so far have all been funded through the development program.
这些钱都是用来资助项目开发的
2015 had the first actual test flight on the Commercial Crew Program
2015年进行了商业载人计划的第一次实际试飞
with SpaceX demonstrating the Dragon to pad abort capability.
也就是SpaceX公司验证了龙飞船的发射场逃逸能力
However in June the CRS 7 mission failed
然而 同年6月份 CRS-7任务失败了
due to the second stage oxygen tank rupturing after a helium cylinder broke phillipe free
由于第二级液氧储罐在(其内部的用于储罐加压的)氦气瓶破裂后解体了
Falcon 9 would be grounded during the investigation and it returned to flight in December.
猎鹰9号将在(问题)调查期间停飞 并在12月恢复飞行
This was a new variant called The Full thrust.
(复飞后的火箭)是一种名为全推力的新种类
This used a deep chilled densified propellant to get more performance from the same size of fuel tanks.
这使用了一种超低温密度更高的推进剂 以从相同大小的燃料储罐中获得更多的性能
This mission would also be the first to successfully land and recover the first stage booster at the launch site.
这次任务也是第一个在发射场成功降落并回收一级火箭的任务
And this booster is the one that's on display at SpaceX headquarters.
而这个一级火箭就是在SpaceX总部展示的那个
By 2016 most of the funding fights over Commercial Crew were over.
到了2016年 大部分商业载人计划的资金斗争都结束了
There did continue to be a steady stream of diehards
确实还有源源不断的顽固分子
looking for any excuse to redirect Commercial Crew funds elsewhere.
寻找任何借口要将商业载人的资金转移到其他地方
SpaceX continued developing as booster recovery.
SpaceX公司继续研发着一级火箭的回收
They landed several boosters over the year on land and on their drone ships.
在2016年 他们的一级火箭在陆地和无人船上进行了着陆
However in september, SpaceX suffered another dramatic failure on the pad
然而在9月份 SpaceX公司又在发射场遭遇了一次戏剧性的失败
when they were loading propellants to test-fire the engines.
当火箭加注推进剂以测试发动机时
There would be no more flights for the year while it was being investigated.
在这之后都处于调查期间 这一年不会再有飞行
In 2017 there was a new president in the White House
2017年 白宫里来了一位新总统
but NASA funding for commercial space operations remained essentially untouched by the new administration.
但NASA对商业太空业务的资助基本上没有受到新政府的影响
Falcon 9 returned to flight and in March it performed the first re-flight of a booster.
猎鹰9号在3月进行了一级火箭的首次复飞
2017 also saw the debut of the Block 4 booster design with its upgraded engines.
实际上block4是指一二级整体的升级，而不仅仅是一级火箭(助推器)
2017年还首次采用了Block 4的一级火箭设计 并对其发动机进行了升级
2018 debuted the Falcon Heavy
2018年 重型猎鹰首次亮相
and while many of you remember the red roadster carrying Starman off on the cruise into deep space,
当很多人还记得那辆红色跑车载着Starman去深空漫游的时候
it wasn't hugely relevant to the Commercial Crew Program.
这与商业载人计划没有太大关系
But later in that year the introduction of the Block 5 version of a Falcon 9 was.
但在那一年的晚些时候 采用了Block 5版本的猎鹰9号
Now Block 5 was supposed to represent the final evolution of the Block Falcon 9.
现在Block 5应该是代表了Block猎鹰9的最终进化
Any stable state that could be approved to fly crew.
任何稳定的状态 都可以被批准进行载人发射
In August of 2018,
在2018年8月的时候
the astronauts who would fly the first missions and commercial crew were announced.
(NASA)宣布了将执行首批商业载人任务的航天员
Of course at that point they were still expecting the astronauts would fly in 2019.
当然那时候他们还在期待航天员会在2019年进行飞行
And 2019 did see the first flight of a Crew Dragon in March.
而2019年3月 载人龙飞船确实进行了首飞
It launched safely and traveled to the space station carrying Ripley, the test dummy
它安全发射 并携带测试假人Ripley前往空间站
and Plushy Earth and some extra cargo.
和毛茸茸的地球玩偶 还有一些额外的货物
The capsule returned to Earth
太空舱返回地球
and was expected to be recovered and refurbished and used for an in-flight abort test.
并预计将被回收和翻新 用于飞行中止试验
But in April a ground test destroyed the capsule in a fiery explosion.
但在4月的一次地面测试中 这个返回舱被一次爆炸摧毁
The investigation would take months
调查将耗时数月
and ultimately require a redesign of the propellant system for their abort thrusters.
并最终需要对其逃逸发动机的推进系统进行重新设计
At the end of 2019 Boeing also performed a test flight of their Starliner spacecraft
在2019年底 波音公司也对其星际客机飞船进行了试飞
and while the launch was perfect,
而虽然(火箭)发射很完美
the capsule had many problems once in space, largely blamed on poorly tested software.
飞船在太空中遇到了很多问题 主要归咎于(之前的)软件测试不当
The capsule never made his planned rendezvous with the station
飞船并未按计划与空间站交会
and there were enough questions raised about the flight
这次试飞产生了足够多的问题
that Boeing is planning a second test flight later this year.
所以波音计划今年晚些时候进行第二次试飞
2019 also saw the launch of the Artemis program
2019年 阿尔忒弥斯计划也将启动
which is expected to use a lot more Commercial Crew capabilities
预计将比SLS最初的支持者在2010年预测的
or commercial launch capabilities than the original backers of the SLS predicted in 2010.
相比商业载人计划或者商业发射系统的能力更多
那么我们就到了2020年
And so we get to 2020.
这是一个漫长的旅程 但这一年以精彩的方式拉开了序幕
It's been a long ride but the year kicked off in spectacular style
在用过的猎鹰9号一级上进行了龙2飞船的飞行中止测试
with the in-flight abort test of the Dragon 2 capsule on an old Falcon 9 booster.
真的就是以科学的名义炸掉了一级火箭
Literally exploding the rocket booster in the name of science.
而这也为龙飞船的首次载人发射铺平了道路
And that paved it away for the first crewed launch of Dragon
bringing to an end the gap in spaceflight that resulted from decisions made almost twenty years ago.
结束了近二十年前的决定所造成的(美国载人)太空飞行的空白
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 祝你安全飞行